# Haofeng Zhang

hz2553@columbia.edu | https://hz0000.github.io/ | Update: 01/18/2024

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My primary research interests are in methodology and theory for data-driven decision-making and prediction at the intersection of operations research, data science, and machine learning. I am particularly interested in the following fields:

- Decision-making under uncertainty, including data-driven contextual optimization and sequential decision-making under uncertainty.
- Uncertainty quantification and reduction, including simulation-based approaches, calibration, distributional robustness and shift.

### **EDUCATION**

Columbia University, New York City, New York

Department of Industrial Engineering and Operations Research

- Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Operations Research

2024

- Master of Science (M.S.) in Operations Research

2019

University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China

Department of Mathematics

- Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

2017

# PUBLICATIONS & WORKING PAPERS

Author ordering in most papers is alphabetical as is convention in OR/IE/MS, while exceptions are marked by \*. Published papers

- Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, and Haofeng Zhang. Efficient Uncertainty Quantification and Reduction for Over-Parameterized Neural Networks. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, Amirhossein Meisami, and **Haofeng Zhang**. Optimal Regret Is Achievable with Bounded Approximate Inference Error: An Enhanced Bayesian Upper Confidence Bound Framework. *Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2023.
- Henry Lam and **Haofeng Zhang**. Doubly Robust Stein-Kernelized Monte Carlo Estimator: Simultaneous Bias-Variance Reduction and Supercanonical Convergence. *Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR)*, 24(85):1-58, 2023.

### New England Statistics Symposium Student Paper Award 2022

- Ziyi Huang, Yu Gan, Theresa Lye, Yanchen Liu, Haofeng Zhang, Andrew Laine, Elsa Angelini, and Christine Hendon.\* Cardiac Adipose Tissue Segmentation via Image-Level Annotations. *IEEE Journal of Biomedical* and Health Informatics (JBHI), 2023.
- Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, and **Haofeng Zhang**. Conditional Coverage Estimation for High-Quality Prediction Intervals. *Journal of Systems Science and Systems Engineering* (Invited Paper to the Special Issue on Simulation and AI), 1-31, 2023.
- Haoxian Chen, Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, Huajie Qian, and **Haofeng Zhang**. Learning Prediction Intervals for Regression: Generalization and Calibration. In *International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS)*, pp. 820-828. PMLR, 2021.
- Henry Lam and Haofeng Zhang. Neural Predictive Intervals for Simulation Metamodeling. In Winter Simulation Conference (WSC), pp. 1-12. IEEE, 2021.
- Ziyi Huang, Haofeng Zhang, Andrew Laine, Elsa Angelini, Christine Hendon, and Yu Gan.\* Co-Seg: An Image Segmentation Framework against Label Corruption. In *IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI)*, pp. 550-553. IEEE, 2021.

- Ziyi Huang, Yu Gan, Theresa Lye, Haofeng Zhang, Andrew Laine, Elsa Angelini, and Christine Hendon.\*
  Heterogeneity Measurement of Cardiac Tissues Leveraging Uncertainty Information from Image Segmentation.
  In International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), pp. 782-791. Springer, Cham, 2020.
- Henry Lam and **Haofeng Zhang**. On the Stability of Kernelized Control Functionals on Partial and Biased Stochastic Inputs. In *Winter Simulation Conference (WSC)*, pp. 344-355. IEEE, 2019.

#### ACM SIGSIM WSC 2019 Student Award 2019

# Papers under review/revision

 Adam N. Elmachtoub, Henry Lam, Haofeng Zhang, and Yunfan Zhao. Estimate-Then-Optimize versus Integrated-Estimation-Optimization versus Sample Average Approximation: A Stochastic Dominance Perspective. Under revision in *Operations Research*.

### Finalist, INFORMS George Nicholson Student Paper Competition 2023

• Henry Lam and **Haofeng Zhang**. Prediction Intervals for Simulation Metamodeling. Under revision in *ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation (TOMACS)*.

## Working papers

- Ziyi Huang and **Haofeng Zhang**. Bayesian Bandit Algorithms with Approximate Inference in Stochastic Linear Bandits.
- Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, Amirhossein Meisami, Haofeng Zhang, Jie Zhang, and Yunfan Zhao. Calibration of Deep Bayesian Bandits via Off-Policy Evaluations.
- Ziyi Huang, Henry Lam, and **Haofeng Zhang**. Validating Stochastic Simulation Models via Maximum Mean Discrepancy.
- Ziyi Huang, Hongshan Liu, Haofeng Zhang, Fuyong Xing, Andrew Laine, Elsa Angelini, Christine Hendon, and Yu Gan.\* Push the Boundary of SAM: A Pseudo-label Correction Framework for Medical Segmentation.

### FUNDING & SELECTED AWARDS

Supports from the following funding sources are gratefully acknowledged:

Cheung-Kong Innovation Doctoral Fellowship 2021-2023 (covering tuition and stipend, approximately \$160K in total)

The following awards are gratefully acknowledged:

- Finalist, INFORMS George Nicholson Student Paper Competition 2023
- NeurIPS Scholar Award 2023
- New England Statistics Symposium Student Paper Award 2022
- ACM SIGSIM WSC 2019 Student Award 2019
- Graduation Thesis Award 2017 (top 3%)
- Undergraduate Research Award 2016 (top 2%)
- National Scholarship 2015 (top 1%)

# PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

- Co-Session Chair: WSC 2022, INFORMS Annual Meeting 2021
- Reviewer or contribute to reviewing:
  - Journals: Applied Probability Journals, INFORMS Journal on Computing, SIAM Journal on Optimization, Operations Research, Management Science.
  - Conferences: AISTATS, IJCAI, ISBI, NeurIPS.

# SELECTED INVITED TALKS

Estimate-Then-Optimize versus Integrated-Estimation-Optimization versus Sample Average Approximation: A Stochastic Dominance Perspective

• INFORMS Optimization Society Conference (Houston TX, 03/2024), INFORMS Annual Meeting (Phoenix AZ, 10/2023), Purdue Research Symposium on Operations (West Lafayette IN, 09/2023), International Conference Stochastic Programming (Davis CA, 07/2023), SIAM Conference on Optimization (Seattle WA, 06/2023).

Doubly Robust Stein-Kernelized Monte Carlo Estimator: Simultaneous Bias-Variance Reduction and Supercanonical Convergence

• New England Statistics Symposium (Storrs CT, 05/2022), INFORMS Annual Meeting (Anaheim CA, 10/2021).

### Validating Stochastic Simulation Models via Maximum Mean Discrepancy

• INFORMS Annual Meeting (Indianapolis IN, 10/2022).

### Learning Prediction Intervals for Regression: Generalization and Calibration

• ICML Workshop on Distribution-Free Uncertainty Quantification (Baltimore MD, 07/2022), INFORMS Annual Meeting (Virtual, 11/2020).

### On the Stability of Kernelized Control Functionals on Partial and Biased Stochastic Inputs

• INFORMS Annual Meeting (Seattle WA, 10/2019).

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

### Data Science Intern at Adobe Inc. (San Jose, CA)

May 2022 - August 2022

• Improve existing algorithms for a personalized recommendation system. Build a new module for model and hyperparameter calibration, introducing off-policy evaluation approaches into deep-learning-based Bayesian bandit algorithms. Investigate algorithm performance in the presence of practical issues, including low click-through rates, approximate Bayesian inference, changing action sets, and delayed feedback.

#### Data Science Intern at Adobe Inc. (San Jose, CA)

May 2021 - August 2021

• Implement and compare multiple contextual bandit algorithms for a personalized recommendation system in practice. Propose a robust deep-learning-based Bayesian bandit algorithm that is effective and computationally efficient.

# Teaching Assistant & Research Assistant at Columbia University (New York, NY)

2018 - 2024

 As a teaching assistant: Introduction to Financial Engineering (Fall 2020); Quantitative Risk Management (Spring 2020); Credit Risks & Credit Derivatives (Fall 2019); Applications Programming for Financial Engineering (Spring 2019, Fall 2018)

### SKILLS

- Python (including Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Scipy, Numpy, Matplotlib);
- $\bullet$ R; C; MATLAB; SQL; LaTeX

### Personal

• Languages: English, Chinese

• Hobbies: Movies, piano, travel